{"description": "Given a DAG (directed acyclic graph) with nodes V, W, L, A and directed edges W->A, V->W, W->L, V->A, L->A.", "questions_and_answers": [{"question_type": "FA", "question": "Find all backdoor paths from node L to node A.", "answer": ["L<-W->A", "L<-W<-V->A"]}, {"question_type": "HM", "question": "How many backdoor paths are from node L to node A.", "answer": "2"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find the shortest backdoor path from node L to node A.", "answer": "L<-W->A"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find the longest backdoor path from node L to node A.", "answer": "L<-W<-V->A"}, {"question_type": "MC", "question": "Which of the following is a backdoor path from W to L?\nA. W->A<-L\nB. W<-V->A<-L\nC. W<-A<->V->L\nD. W->L", "answer": "B"}, {"question_type": "YN", "question": "Is W<-V->A a backdoor path from W to A?", "answer": "Yes."}], "uid": "72212724", "graph_type": "DAG"}
{"description": "Given a DAG (directed acyclic graph) with nodes Q, N, F, K and directed edges Q->F, Q->N, N->F, N->K, Q->K.", "questions_and_answers": [{"question_type": "FA", "question": "Find all backdoor paths from node N to node F.", "answer": ["N<-Q->F"]}, {"question_type": "HM", "question": "How many backdoor paths are from node N to node K.", "answer": "1"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find the shortest backdoor path from node N to node K.", "answer": "N<-Q->K"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find the longest backdoor path from node N to node K.", "answer": "N<-Q->K"}, {"question_type": "MC", "question": "Which of the following is a backdoor path from N to K?\nA. N<-Q->K\nB. N->F<-Q->K\nC. N->K\nD. N<->Q<->F<-K", "answer": "A"}, {"question_type": "YN", "question": "Is N<-Q->K a backdoor path from N to K?", "answer": "Yes."}], "uid": "38635416", "graph_type": "DAG"}
{"description": "Given a DAG (directed acyclic graph) with nodes B, D, T, K, G and directed edges T->K, B->G, T->G, D->K, B->D, D->T.", "questions_and_answers": [{"question_type": "FA", "question": "Find all backdoor paths from node D to node G.", "answer": ["D<-B->G"]}, {"question_type": "HM", "question": "How many backdoor paths are from node T to node G.", "answer": "1"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find the shortest backdoor path from node D to node T.", "answer": "D<-B->G<-T"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find the longest backdoor path from node D to node T.", "answer": "D<-B->G<-T"}, {"question_type": "MC", "question": "Which of the following is a backdoor path from D to T?\nA. D<->B<->K<-T\nB. D<-B->G<-T\nC. D->K<-T\nD. D->T", "answer": "B"}, {"question_type": "YN", "question": "Is D<-B->G<-T a backdoor path from D to T?", "answer": "Yes."}], "uid": "41720728", "graph_type": "DAG"}
{"description": "Given a DAG (directed acyclic graph) with nodes P, M, I, X, R and directed edges I->R, I->X, M->X, P->M, P->I.", "questions_and_answers": [{"question_type": "FA", "question": "Find all backdoor paths from node M to node X.", "answer": ["M<-P->I->X"]}, {"question_type": "HM", "question": "How many backdoor paths are from node M to node X.", "answer": "1"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find the shortest backdoor path from node I to node X.", "answer": "I<-P->M->X"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find the longest backdoor path from node I to node X.", "answer": "I<-P->M->X"}, {"question_type": "MC", "question": "Which of the following is a backdoor path from I to X?\nA. I<-P->M->X\nB. I->X\nC. I<->R->X\nD. I<->M<->P<->X", "answer": "A"}, {"question_type": "YN", "question": "Is I->R a backdoor path from I to R?", "answer": "No."}], "uid": "22376943", "graph_type": "DAG"}
{"description": "Given a DAG (directed acyclic graph) with nodes G, X, U, H, O, S and directed edges X->U, G->O, U->S, O->S, X->S, G->H, G->X, G->U, U->O.", "questions_and_answers": [{"question_type": "FA", "question": "Find all backdoor paths from node O to node S.", "answer": ["O<-U->S", "O<-G->U->S", "O<-G->X->S", "O<-U<-X->S", "O<-G->U<-X->S", "O<-G->X->U->S", "O<-U<-G->X->S"]}, {"question_type": "HM", "question": "How many backdoor paths are from node X to node U.", "answer": "3"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find the shortest backdoor path from node X to node O.", "answer": "X<-G->O"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find the longest backdoor path from node X to node O.", "answer": "X<-G->U->S<-O"}, {"question_type": "MC", "question": "Which of the following is a backdoor path from U to S?\nA. U->O<-G->X->S\nB. U->S\nC. U<-G->X->S\nD. U->O->S", "answer": "C"}, {"question_type": "YN", "question": "Is X<-G->U->O a backdoor path from X to O?", "answer": "Yes."}], "uid": "27014256", "graph_type": "DAG"}
{"description": "Given a DAG (directed acyclic graph) with nodes D, Y, Q, P, C, L and directed edges C->L, D->L, D->Y, Q->P, Y->C, Y->P, P->L, D->C.", "questions_and_answers": [{"question_type": "FA", "question": "Find all backdoor paths from node P to node L.", "answer": ["P<-Y<-D->L", "P<-Y->C->L", "P<-Y<-D->C->L", "P<-Y->C<-D->L"]}, {"question_type": "HM", "question": "How many backdoor paths are from node C to node L.", "answer": "4"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find the shortest backdoor path from node C to node L.", "answer": "C<-D->L"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find the longest backdoor path from node C to node L.", "answer": "C<-D->Y->P->L"}, {"question_type": "MC", "question": "Which of the following is a backdoor path from Y to C?\nA. Y->P->L<-D->C\nB. Y->C\nC. Y->P->L<-C\nD. Y<-D->L<-C", "answer": "D"}, {"question_type": "YN", "question": "Is Y->P a backdoor path from Y to P?", "answer": "No."}], "uid": "30902466", "graph_type": "DAG"}
{"description": "Given a DAG (directed acyclic graph) with nodes S, A, P, V, H, L, G and directed edges S->H, P->G, A->L, P->L, L->G, A->P, V->L, H->L, P->H, V->H, V->G, A->G.", "questions_and_answers": [{"question_type": "FA", "question": "Find all backdoor paths from node H to node G.", "answer": ["H<-V->G", "H<-P->G", "H<-V->L->G", "H<-P->L->G", "H<-P<-A->G", "H<-V->L<-P->G", "H<-V->L<-A->G", "H<-P->L<-V->G", "H<-P->L<-A->G", "H<-P<-A->L->G", "H<-V->L<-P<-A->G", "H<-V->L<-A->P->G", "H<-P<-A->L<-V->G"]}, {"question_type": "HM", "question": "How many backdoor paths are from node P to node H.", "answer": "7"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find the shortest backdoor path from node P to node G.", "answer": "P<-A->G"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find the longest backdoor path from node P to node G.", "answer": "P<-A->L<-H<-V->G"}, {"question_type": "MC", "question": "Which of the following is a backdoor path from L to G?\nA. L->A<-H->P<-V<-G\nB. L<-V->H<-P<-A->G\nC. L<->S<-V->P<->G\nD. L->G", "answer": "B"}, {"question_type": "YN", "question": "Is P->H->L<-V->G a backdoor path from P to G?", "answer": "No."}], "uid": "95745142", "graph_type": "DAG"}
{"description": "Given a DAG (directed acyclic graph) with nodes I, L, Z, G, T, K, R and directed edges L->G, Z->T, T->R, L->R, K->R, Z->K, T->K, I->L, Z->R, Z->G, L->T, I->T.", "questions_and_answers": [{"question_type": "FA", "question": "Find all backdoor paths from node L to node T.", "answer": ["L<-I->T"]}, {"question_type": "HM", "question": "How many backdoor paths are from node L to node G.", "answer": "5"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find the shortest backdoor path from node T to node R.", "answer": "T<-Z->R"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find the longest backdoor path from node T to node R.", "answer": "T<-I->L->G<-Z->K->R"}, {"question_type": "MC", "question": "Which of the following is a backdoor path from L to R?\nA. L->G<-Z->K->R\nB. L->G<-Z->K<-T->R\nC. L<-I->T<-Z->K->R\nD. L->G<-Z->T->K->R", "answer": "C"}, {"question_type": "YN", "question": "Is K->R a backdoor path from K to R?", "answer": "No."}], "uid": "15286643", "graph_type": "DAG"}
{"description": "Given a DAG (directed acyclic graph) with nodes U, N, W, Y, T, L, B, C and directed edges U->T, U->W, W->L, N->C, N->B, U->B, N->L, Y->B, T->L, L->B, B->C.", "questions_and_answers": [{"question_type": "FA", "question": "Find all backdoor paths from node L to node C.", "answer": ["L<-N->C", "L<-N->B->C", "L<-W<-U->B->C", "L<-T<-U->B->C", "L<-W<-U->B<-N->C", "L<-T<-U->B<-N->C"]}, {"question_type": "HM", "question": "How many backdoor paths are from node T to node C.", "answer": "7"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find the shortest backdoor path from node T to node C.", "answer": "T<-U->B->C"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find the longest backdoor path from node T to node C.", "answer": "T<-U->W->L->B<-N->C"}, {"question_type": "MC", "question": "Which of the following is a backdoor path from L to C?\nA. L->B<-N->C\nB. L<->W->B->N<->T<-C\nC. L<-W<-U->B<-N->C\nD. L->B->C", "answer": "C"}, {"question_type": "YN", "question": "Is L->B a backdoor path from L to B?", "answer": "No."}], "uid": "43606949", "graph_type": "DAG"}
{"description": "Given a DAG (directed acyclic graph) with nodes K, V, Z, D, O, I, B, M and directed edges K->D, O->B, K->I, D->M, V->O, K->Z, K->V, D->O.", "questions_and_answers": [{"question_type": "FA", "question": "Find all backdoor paths from node V to node O.", "answer": ["V<-K->D->O"]}, {"question_type": "HM", "question": "How many backdoor paths are from node D to node B.", "answer": "1"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find the shortest backdoor path from node V to node O.", "answer": "V<-K->D->O"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find the longest backdoor path from node V to node O.", "answer": "V<-K->D->O"}, {"question_type": "MC", "question": "Which of the following is a backdoor path from V to B?\nA. V<->M->K<-D<-O->B\nB. V<-K->D->O->B\nC. V<-Z<->B\nD. V->O->B", "answer": "B"}, {"question_type": "YN", "question": "Is V->O a backdoor path from V to O?", "answer": "No."}], "uid": "54234933", "graph_type": "DAG"}
{"description": "Given a DAG (directed acyclic graph) with nodes C, Y, X, K, U, O, W, B, L and directed edges Y->O, C->U, Y->L, X->O, Y->K, Y->X, O->W, X->B, C->X, K->B, U->W, Y->B.", "questions_and_answers": [{"question_type": "FA", "question": "Find all backdoor paths from node O to node W.", "answer": ["O<-X<-C->U->W", "O<-Y->X<-C->U->W", "O<-Y->B<-X<-C->U->W", "O<-Y->K->B<-X<-C->U->W"]}, {"question_type": "HM", "question": "How many backdoor paths are from node U to node W.", "answer": "4"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find the shortest backdoor path from node U to node W.", "answer": "U<-C->X->O->W"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find the longest backdoor path from node U to node W.", "answer": "U<-C->X->B<-K<-Y->O->W"}, {"question_type": "MC", "question": "Which of the following is a backdoor path from X to W?\nA. X->B<-K<-Y->O->W\nB. X<-C->U->W\nC. X->B<-Y->O->W\nD. X->O->W", "answer": "B"}, {"question_type": "YN", "question": "Is X->B<-K<-Y->O->W a backdoor path from X to W?", "answer": "No."}], "uid": "88416959", "graph_type": "DAG"}
{"description": "Given a DAG (directed acyclic graph) with nodes N, K, T, Q, M, U, W, P, X and directed edges M->U, N->W, Q->X, Q->P, N->K, N->T, Q->U, T->M, N->Q.", "questions_and_answers": [{"question_type": "FA", "question": "Find all backdoor paths from node M to node U.", "answer": ["M<-T<-N->Q->U"]}, {"question_type": "HM", "question": "How many backdoor paths are from node Q to node U.", "answer": "1"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find the shortest backdoor path from node T to node M.", "answer": "T<-N->Q->U<-M"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find the longest backdoor path from node T to node M.", "answer": "T<-N->Q->U<-M"}, {"question_type": "MC", "question": "Which of the following is a backdoor path from T to M?\nA. T<-N->Q->U<-M\nB. T<->U<-Q->N<-W<-X<-M\nC. T<-U<-P<->X<->N->Q<->K<-W<-M\nD. T->M", "answer": "A"}, {"question_type": "YN", "question": "Is T<-N->Q->U<-M a backdoor path from T to M?", "answer": "Yes."}], "uid": "72179857", "graph_type": "DAG"}
{"description": "Given an ADMG (acyclic directed mixed graph) with nodes G, K, U, L, directed edges G->L, G->U, G->K, U->L and bi-directed edges K<->L.", "questions_and_answers": [{"question_type": "FA", "question": "Find all backdoor paths from node U to node L.", "answer": ["U<-G->L", "U<-G->K<->L"]}, {"question_type": "HM", "question": "How many backdoor paths are from node U to node L.", "answer": "2"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find the shortest backdoor path from node U to node L.", "answer": "U<-G->L"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find the longest backdoor path from node U to node L.", "answer": "U<-G->K<->L"}, {"question_type": "MC", "question": "Which of the following is a backdoor path from U to L?\nA. U->L\nB. U<->K->L\nC. U<-G->K<->L\nD. U<-G<->K<-L", "answer": "C"}, {"question_type": "YN", "question": "Is U<-G->L a backdoor path from U to L?", "answer": "Yes."}], "uid": "53270121", "graph_type": "ADMG"}
{"description": "Given an ADMG (acyclic directed mixed graph) with nodes K, F, V, C, directed edges F->C, K->F, V->C and bi-directed edges K<->C.", "questions_and_answers": [{"question_type": "FA", "question": "Find all backdoor paths from node F to node C.", "answer": ["F<-K<->C"]}, {"question_type": "HM", "question": "How many backdoor paths are from node F to node C.", "answer": "1"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find the shortest backdoor path from node F to node C.", "answer": "F<-K<->C"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find the longest backdoor path from node F to node C.", "answer": "F<-K<->C"}, {"question_type": "MC", "question": "Which of the following is a backdoor path from F to C?\nA. F<-K<->C\nB. F->C\nC. F->V<->C\nD. F<->K->V<->C", "answer": "A"}, {"question_type": "YN", "question": "Is F->C a backdoor path from F to C?", "answer": "No."}], "uid": "83914130", "graph_type": "ADMG"}
{"description": "Given an ADMG (acyclic directed mixed graph) with nodes V, D, W, N, F, directed edges W->N, D->F, V->D, V->F, W->F, D->W, V->W, V->N, D->N and bi-directed edges D<->F, W<->N, D<->N.", "questions_and_answers": [{"question_type": "FA", "question": "Find all backdoor paths from node D to node F.", "answer": ["D<->F", "D<-V->F", "D<->N<-W->F", "D<->N<->W->F", "D<->N<-V->F", "D<-V->W->F", "D<->N<-W<-V->F", "D<->N<->W<-V->F", "D<->N<-V->W->F", "D<-V->N<-W->F", "D<-V->N<->W->F"]}, {"question_type": "HM", "question": "How many backdoor paths are from node D to node F.", "answer": "11"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find the shortest backdoor path from node W to node F.", "answer": "W<-D->F"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find the longest backdoor path from node W to node F.", "answer": "W<-V->N<->D<->F"}, {"question_type": "MC", "question": "Which of the following is a backdoor path from W to N?\nA. W->F<->D<-V->N\nB. W<-V->N\nC. W->F<-V->D<->N\nD. W->F<-V->D->N", "answer": "B"}, {"question_type": "YN", "question": "Is D<-V->F<-W a backdoor path from D to W?", "answer": "Yes."}], "uid": "79360393", "graph_type": "ADMG"}
{"description": "Given an ADMG (acyclic directed mixed graph) with nodes U, V, H, R, Z, directed edges H->Z, U->H, H->R, V->Z, U->Z, V->H, U->R, R->Z, V->R, U->V and bi-directed edges H<->Z, U<->Z, V<->R, U<->R.", "questions_and_answers": [{"question_type": "FA", "question": "Find all backdoor paths from node R to node Z.", "answer": ["R<-U->Z", "R<-U<->Z", "R<->U->Z", "R<->U<->Z", "R<-V->Z", "R<->V->Z", "R<-H->Z", "R<-H<->Z", "R<-U->V->Z", "R<-U->H->Z", "R<-U->H<->Z", "R<->U->V->Z", "R<->U->H->Z", "R<->U->H<->Z", "R<-V<-U->Z", "R<-V<-U<->Z", "R<-V->H->Z", "R<-V->H<->Z", "R<->V<-U->Z", "R<->V<-U<->Z", "R<->V->H->Z", "R<->V->H<->Z", "R<-H<-U->Z", "R<-H<-U<->Z", "R<-H<-V->Z", "R<-U->V->H->Z", "R<-U->V->H<->Z", "R<-U->H<-V->Z", "R<->U->V->H->Z", "R<->U->V->H<->Z", "R<->U->H<-V->Z", "R<-V<-U->H->Z", "R<-V<-U->H<->Z", "R<-V->H<-U->Z", "R<-V->H<-U<->Z", "R<->V<-U->H->Z", "R<->V<-U->H<->Z", "R<->V->H<-U->Z", "R<->V->H<-U<->Z", "R<-H<-U->V->Z", "R<-H<-V<-U->Z", "R<-H<-V<-U<->Z"]}, {"question_type": "HM", "question": "How many backdoor paths are from node V to node R.", "answer": "12"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find the shortest backdoor path from node V to node Z.", "answer": "V<-U->Z"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find the longest backdoor path from node V to node Z.", "answer": "V<->R<->U->H<->Z"}, {"question_type": "MC", "question": "Which of the following is a backdoor path from H to Z?\nA. H<-U->V->Z\nB. H->R<->V<-U<->Z\nC. H->R<->V->Z\nD. H->R<->V<-U->Z", "answer": "A"}, {"question_type": "YN", "question": "Is V<-U->R<-H a backdoor path from V to H?", "answer": "Yes."}], "uid": "17115292", "graph_type": "ADMG"}
{"description": "Given an ADMG (acyclic directed mixed graph) with nodes Y, B, G, L, S, M, directed edges B->M, L->S, Y->S, B->L, B->S, G->S, B->G, Y->G, Y->M, S->M and bi-directed edges Y<->G.", "questions_and_answers": [{"question_type": "FA", "question": "Find all backdoor paths from node L to node S.", "answer": ["L<-B->S", "L<-B->G->S", "L<-B->M<-S", "L<-B->G<-Y->S", "L<-B->G<->Y->S", "L<-B->M<-Y->S", "L<-B->G<-Y->M<-S", "L<-B->G<->Y->M<-S", "L<-B->M<-Y->G->S", "L<-B->M<-Y<->G->S"]}, {"question_type": "HM", "question": "How many backdoor paths are from node L to node S.", "answer": "10"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find the shortest backdoor path from node S to node M.", "answer": "S<-B->M"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find the longest backdoor path from node S to node M.", "answer": "S<-L<-B->G<->Y->M"}, {"question_type": "MC", "question": "Which of the following is a backdoor path from S to M?\nA. S->M\nB. S<-L<-B->G<-Y->M\nC. S<->L<-M\nD. S<-B->Y->L<-G->M", "answer": "B"}, {"question_type": "YN", "question": "Is G->S a backdoor path from G to S?", "answer": "No."}], "uid": "55364731", "graph_type": "ADMG"}
{"description": "Given an ADMG (acyclic directed mixed graph) with nodes B, O, A, I, W, E, directed edges B->E, I->E, O->I, B->A, O->A, A->I, A->W, A->E, O->E, I->W, B->O, B->W and bi-directed edges O<->A, B<->E.", "questions_and_answers": [{"question_type": "FA", "question": "Find all backdoor paths from node I to node W.", "answer": ["I<-A->W", "I<-A<-B->W", "I<-O<-B->W", "I<-O->A->W", "I<-O<->A->W", "I<-A->E<-B->W", "I<-A->E<->B->W", "I<-A<-O<-B->W", "I<-A<->O<-B->W", "I<-O->E<-B->W", "I<-O->E<->B->W", "I<-O->E<-A->W", "I<-O<-B->A->W", "I<-O->A<-B->W", "I<-O<->A<-B->W", "I<-A->E<-O<-B->W", "I<-A<-O->E<-B->W", "I<-A<-O->E<->B->W", "I<-A<->O->E<-B->W", "I<-A<->O->E<->B->W", "I<-O->E<-B->A->W", "I<-O->E<->B->A->W", "I<-O->E<-A<-B->W", "I<-O<-B->E<-A->W", "I<-O<-B<->E<-A->W", "I<-O->A->E<-B->W", "I<-O->A->E<->B->W", "I<-O<->A->E<-B->W", "I<-O<->A->E<->B->W"]}, {"question_type": "HM", "question": "How many backdoor paths are from node O to node A.", "answer": "11"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find the shortest backdoor path from node O to node I.", "answer": "O<->A->I"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find the longest backdoor path from node O to node I.", "answer": "O<->A->W<-B<->E<-I"}, {"question_type": "MC", "question": "Which of the following is a backdoor path from O to I?\nA. O->E<-B->A->W<-I\nB. O->A->W<-B->E<-I\nC. O->E<->B->A->W<-I\nD. O<->A->I", "answer": "D"}, {"question_type": "YN", "question": "Is I<-O->E<->B->W a backdoor path from I to W?", "answer": "Yes."}], "uid": "75224824", "graph_type": "ADMG"}
{"description": "Given an ADMG (acyclic directed mixed graph) with nodes G, C, P, K, H, R, O, directed edges H->R, C->H, P->R, P->K, C->P, C->O, G->O, P->H, C->K, K->R, H->O, P->O and bi-directed edges C<->R, G<->R.", "questions_and_answers": [{"question_type": "FA", "question": "Find all backdoor paths from node P to node R.", "answer": ["P<-C<->R", "P<-C->K->R", "P<-C->H->R", "P<-C->O<-G<->R", "P<-C->O<-H->R", "P<-C->H->O<-G<->R"]}, {"question_type": "HM", "question": "How many backdoor paths are from node P to node K.", "answer": "6"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find the shortest backdoor path from node P to node R.", "answer": "P<-C<->R"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find the longest backdoor path from node P to node R.", "answer": "P<-C->H->O<-G<->R"}, {"question_type": "MC", "question": "Which of the following is a backdoor path from H to O?\nA. H->R<-K<-P->O\nB. H->R<-K<-C->O\nC. H<-C<->R<-K<-P->O\nD. H->R<-P->O", "answer": "C"}, {"question_type": "YN", "question": "Is H->O<-C->P->K->R a backdoor path from H to R?", "answer": "No."}], "uid": "50835326", "graph_type": "ADMG"}
{"description": "Given an ADMG (acyclic directed mixed graph) with nodes Q, E, X, Y, M, N, H, directed edges E->Y, Q->Y, X->M, E->X, Q->E, Y->M, Q->N, Q->M, E->N, Q->H, N->H and bi-directed edges Q<->Y, E<->Y, X<->M.", "questions_and_answers": [{"question_type": "FA", "question": "Find all backdoor paths from node X to node M.", "answer": ["X<->M", "X<-E<-Q->M", "X<-E->Y->M", "X<-E<->Y->M", "X<-E<-Q->Y->M", "X<-E<-Q<->Y->M", "X<-E->Y<-Q->M", "X<-E->Y<->Q->M", "X<-E<->Y<-Q->M", "X<-E<->Y<->Q->M", "X<-E->N<-Q->M", "X<-E->N<-Q->Y->M", "X<-E->N<-Q<->Y->M", "X<-E->N->H<-Q->M", "X<-E->N->H<-Q->Y->M", "X<-E->N->H<-Q<->Y->M"]}, {"question_type": "HM", "question": "How many backdoor paths are from node E to node H.", "answer": "8"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find the shortest backdoor path from node N to node H.", "answer": "N<-Q->H"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find the longest backdoor path from node N to node H.", "answer": "N<-E->X<->M<-Y<->Q->H"}, {"question_type": "MC", "question": "Which of the following is a backdoor path from E to H?\nA. E<->Y<->Q->H\nB. E->Y->M<-Q->H\nC. E->X->M<-Y<-Q->N->H\nD. E->X<->M<-Y<->Q->H", "answer": "A"}, {"question_type": "YN", "question": "Is E->Y<-Q->N a backdoor path from E to N?", "answer": "No."}], "uid": "02928234", "graph_type": "ADMG"}
{"description": "Given an ADMG (acyclic directed mixed graph) with nodes M, R, D, U, I, P, E, Z, directed edges R->Z, D->Z, I->P, E->Z, M->U, M->Z, U->Z, I->Z, D->P, M->E and bi-directed edges U<->P, M<->E.", "questions_and_answers": [{"question_type": "FA", "question": "Find all backdoor paths from node E to node Z.", "answer": ["E<-M->Z", "E<->M->Z", "E<-M->U->Z", "E<->M->U->Z", "E<-M->U<->P<-D->Z", "E<-M->U<->P<-I->Z", "E<->M->U<->P<-D->Z", "E<->M->U<->P<-I->Z"]}, {"question_type": "HM", "question": "How many backdoor paths are from node E to node Z.", "answer": "8"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find the shortest backdoor path from node U to node Z.", "answer": "U<-M->Z"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find the longest backdoor path from node U to node Z.", "answer": "U<->P<-D->Z"}, {"question_type": "MC", "question": "Which of the following is a backdoor path from U to Z?\nA. U<-I->D<-P<->E<->M<-R<->Z\nB. U->Z\nC. U<-M->E->Z\nD. U<->R->I<-M->Z", "answer": "C"}, {"question_type": "YN", "question": "Is U<-M->Z a backdoor path from U to Z?", "answer": "Yes."}], "uid": "90551758", "graph_type": "ADMG"}
{"description": "Given an ADMG (acyclic directed mixed graph) with nodes K, A, Y, M, I, S, D, R, directed edges A->I, K->M, A->D, D->R, A->Y, M->S, K->S, Y->M, S->R, A->S, Y->D and bi-directed edges Y<->R, D<->R, A<->Y, A<->S, K<->Y, I<->S, A<->D.", "questions_and_answers": [{"question_type": "FA", "question": "Find all backdoor paths from node Y to node R.", "answer": ["Y<->R", "Y<->K->S->R", "Y<-A->D->R", "Y<-A->D<->R", "Y<-A<->D->R", "Y<-A<->D<->R", "Y<-A->S->R", "Y<-A<->S->R", "Y<->A->D->R", "Y<->A->D<->R", "Y<->A<->D->R", "Y<->A<->D<->R", "Y<->A->S->R", "Y<->A<->S->R", "Y<->K->M->S->R", "Y<-A->I<->S->R", "Y<->A->I<->S->R", "Y<->K->S<-A->D->R", "Y<->K->S<-A->D<->R", "Y<->K->S<-A<->D->R", "Y<->K->S<-A<->D<->R", "Y<->K->S<->A->D->R", "Y<->K->S<->A->D<->R", "Y<->K->S<->A<->D->R", "Y<->K->S<->A<->D<->R", "Y<->K->S<->I<-A->D->R", "Y<->K->S<->I<-A->D<->R", "Y<->K->S<->I<-A<->D->R", "Y<->K->S<->I<-A<->D<->R", "Y<->K->M->S<-A->D->R", "Y<->K->M->S<-A->D<->R", "Y<->K->M->S<-A<->D->R", "Y<->K->M->S<-A<->D<->R", "Y<->K->M->S<->A->D->R", "Y<->K->M->S<->A->D<->R", "Y<->K->M->S<->A<->D->R", "Y<->K->M->S<->A<->D<->R", "Y<->K->M->S<->I<-A->D->R", "Y<->K->M->S<->I<-A->D<->R", "Y<->K->M->S<->I<-A<->D->R", "Y<->K->M->S<->I<-A<->D<->R"]}, {"question_type": "HM", "question": "How many backdoor paths are from node M to node S.", "answer": "72"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find the shortest backdoor path from node S to node R.", "answer": "S<-A->D->R"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find the longest backdoor path from node S to node R.", "answer": "S<-M<-K<->Y<->A<->D<->R"}, {"question_type": "MC", "question": "Which of the following is a backdoor path from Y to R?\nA. Y<->K->M->S<->A->D<->R\nB. Y->M<-K->S<->I<-A<->D->R\nC. Y->M->S<-A->D->R\nD. Y->M<-K->S<-A<->D->R", "answer": "A"}, {"question_type": "YN", "question": "Is Y<->A->S a backdoor path from Y to S?", "answer": "Yes."}], "uid": "62087386", "graph_type": "ADMG"}
{"description": "Given an ADMG (acyclic directed mixed graph) with nodes C, N, I, O, X, K, R, P, Q, directed edges O->K, N->P, X->Q, O->P, C->O, K->R, N->Q, I->Q, X->R, I->X, R->P, X->P and bi-directed edges O<->R.", "questions_and_answers": [{"question_type": "FA", "question": "Find all backdoor paths from node O to node P.", "answer": ["O<->R->P", "O<->R<-X->P", "O<->R<-X->Q<-N->P", "O<->R<-X<-I->Q<-N->P"]}, {"question_type": "HM", "question": "How many backdoor paths are from node O to node P.", "answer": "4"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find the shortest backdoor path from node K to node R.", "answer": "K<-O<->R"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find the longest backdoor path from node K to node R.", "answer": "K<-O->P<-N->Q<-I->X->R"}, {"question_type": "MC", "question": "Which of the following is a backdoor path from R to P?\nA. R->K->Q<->I<->X->C<->N->O->P\nB. R<-X->P\nC. R<->X<->C<->I<->O<-Q->P\nD. R->P", "answer": "B"}, {"question_type": "YN", "question": "Is K->R a backdoor path from K to R?", "answer": "No."}], "uid": "71298855", "graph_type": "ADMG"}
{"description": "Given an ADMG (acyclic directed mixed graph) with nodes N, B, P, H, X, D, J, L, K, directed edges J->K, B->L, B->D, H->D, N->P, P->K, P->X, N->D, N->B, N->H and bi-directed edges X<->D, B<->J.", "questions_and_answers": [{"question_type": "FA", "question": "Find all backdoor paths from node B to node D.", "answer": ["B<-N->D", "B<-N->H->D", "B<-N->P->X<->D", "B<->J->K<-P->X<->D", "B<->J->K<-P<-N->D", "B<->J->K<-P<-N->H->D"]}, {"question_type": "HM", "question": "How many backdoor paths are from node H to node D.", "answer": "5"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find the shortest backdoor path from node P to node X.", "answer": "P<-N->D<->X"}, {"question_type": "FO", "question": "Find the longest backdoor path from node P to node X.", "answer": "P<-N->B->D<->X"}, {"question_type": "MC", "question": "Which of the following is a backdoor path from B to D?\nA. B<-X->P->N->K<->H->L<->J<->D\nB. B<->N<-H<-J<-P->K<-L<-X<->D\nC. B<-N->P->X<->D\nD. B->D", "answer": "C"}, {"question_type": "YN", "question": "Is B->D a backdoor path from B to D?", "answer": "No."}], "uid": "32299919", "graph_type": "ADMG"}
